Guide to the Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lucy Kramer Cohen papers
1900-2005
WA MSS S-2635
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
43.54
(49 boxes) + 7 record album storage
The Lucy Kramer Cohen papers document her decades-long career in the federal government, including her contributions to The Handbook of Federal Indian Law and her work on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas and for the War Labor Board and the Public Health Service, as well as her various professional activities and affiliations as an anthropologist and later as an artist, including her work with the artist and sculptor Pietro Lazzari. The collection consists largely of professional correspondence and memoranda, reports and analyses for various government agencies and projects, conference proceedings, printed material stemming from Kramer Cohen's government employment and organizational affiliations, manuscripts for Felix S. Cohen's The Legal Conscience, which she edited, and various employment papers, including applications, wage records, CV drafts, and employer recommendations. Also found are personal and family papers, which include correspondence between and received by Kramer Cohen and Felix S. Cohen, clippings of obituaries, material relating to the memorial service for Felix S. Cohen, legal and financial documents relating to Kramer Cohen's father's estate and affairs, and property records. Other papers of Felix S. Cohen include research material, clippings, and correspondence relating to Puerto Rico and the Spanish Civil War. Audiovisual materials include a film and reel-to-reel recordings of of Felix Cohen and audiodiscs of his memorial service.
Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007
Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Karen Holmes and Gene Tweraser, 2009, 2014.
Associated Materials
Felix S. Cohen Papers (WA MSS S-1325). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Felix S. Cohen Papers Addition (WA MSS S-2602). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Lucy Kramer Cohen (1907-2007)
Lucy Kramer Cohen was born in Brooklyn, New York, graduated from Barnard College in 1928, and earned her Master's degree in 1929 in mathematics and anthropology at Columbia University. She married Felix S. Cohen, a lawyer, in 1931, and they had two daughters, Karen and Gene. Kramer Cohen worked as an unpaid assistant with her husband in the United States Department of the Interior, helping to draft the Indian Reorganization Act of 1934 and The Handbook of Federal Indian Law in 1942. She was on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas (D-Calif.) during Douglas's three terms in the House from 1944 to 1950. Kramer Cohen also worked for the War Labor Board, the Office of Price Administration, the State Department and the Public Health Service, where she wrote and edited reports in its office of data analysis and management. She also did research work for anthropologists in Washington in between her government jobs, and did researching and writing for Interior Secretary Harold Ickes. She collected, edited, and published her husband's work as The Legal Conscience (New Haven, Yale University Press: 1960) after his death in 1953. She served on the board of directors of the Association on American Indian Affairs from 1961 to 1994. Kramer Cohen officially retired from the federal government in 1977, but continued to work on contract until her actual retirement in 1989. In her later years, she took up drawing and painting, and served as editor of the Washington Watercolor Association newsletter. She died of a stroke in 2007.
Scope and Contents
The Lucy Kramer Cohen papers document her decades-long career in the federal government, including her contributions to The Handbook of Federal Indian Law and her work on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas and for the War Labor Board and the Public Health Service. They also document her various professional activities and affiliations as an anthropologist and later as an artist, including her work with the Association on American Indian Affairs and with the artist and sculptor Pietro Lazzari. The collection consists largely of professional correspondence and memoranda, reports and analysis for various government agencies and projects, conference proceedings, printed material stemming from Kramer Cohen's government employment and organizational affiliations, manuscripts for Felix S. Cohen's The Legal Conscience, which she edited, and various employment papers, including applications, wage records, CV drafts, and employer recommendations. Also present are personal and family papers, which include correspondence between and received by Kramer Cohen and Felix S. Cohen, clippings of obituaries, material relating to the memorial service for Felix S. Cohen, legal and financial documents relating to Kramer Cohen's father's estate and affairs, and property records. Other papers of Felix S. Cohen include research material, clippings, and correspondence relating to Puerto Rico and the Spanish Civil War. Audiovisual materials include a film and reel-to-reel recordings of of Felix Cohen and audiodiscs of his memorial service.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: November 2009 Acquisition; and June 2014 Acquisition.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 49-56 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Civil service -- United States; Indians of North America -- Government relations -- 1934-; Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Anthropologists -- United States; Women anthropologists -- United States; United States -- Politics and government -- 1933-1945; Audiovisual materials; Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007; Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953; Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 ( Felix S. Cohen's Handbook of federal Indian law); Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 ( Legal conscience); Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1900-1980; Lazzari, Pietro, 1898-1979; Association on American Indian Affairs; United States. Department of the Interior; United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945); United States. Public Health Service
- November 2009 Acquisition, 1902-2005; 35; (36 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This accession is not arranged in any particular order.
  - Correspondence, 1933-1934; 4 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936; 4 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1939; 4 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (labeled "misc.-important"), 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1932 (Box 1)
  - Felix and Lucy Activities, 1930s (Box 1)
  - Felix and Lucy Activities, 1930s; 2 (Box 2)
  - Misc. from Lucy Kramer Cohen's top desk drawer, 1935-1937; 2 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript, "Machines & Tools", 1932 (Box 2)
  - Music manuscript notebook, circa 1933 (Box 2)
  - "A survey of social problems in the production and consumption of food," Industrial Research Group, circa 1933 (Box 2)
  - Activities, Industrial Research Group, writings and correspondence, 1930s; 3 (Box 2)
  - NAACP/lynching, writings and correspondence, circa 1938 (Box 2)
  - Student Summer Forum, writings, correspondence and printed material, 1920s-1930s (Box 2)
  - "The Logic of Semantics," annotated printed material from The Journal of Philosophy, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Course notes, statistics and logic, circa 1932 (Box 2)
  - "The New Orleans Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science," printed material from The Scientific Monthly, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Scientific journal reprints, 1916-1932 (Box 2)
  - Felix S. and Lucy K. Cohen Activities, 1930s (Box 2)
  - League for Industrial Democracy button, 1930s (Box 2)
  - Lucy and Felix activities, League for Industrial Democracy, etc., 1930s; 2 (Box 2)
  - Industrial Research Group correspondence, 1932-1934; 1 (Box 2)
  - Industrial Research Group correspondence, 1932-1934; 1 (Box 3)
  - Membership cards, 1934-1959 (Box 3)
  - Capital City Forum, circa 1936; 4 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, correspondence, circa 1936 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, files, circa 1929 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group files, Fabian Society, 1932-1934 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, correspondence, 1932-1935 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, files, circa 1930 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, manuscripts and papers, 1930s (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, manuscripts and papers, undated (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, correspondence and manuscripts, 1930s (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, "Perishable Foods"-early drafts, 1930s (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group files, proposed constitutions, charters, bylaws (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group files, correspondence, 1930-1937 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group files, manuscript drafts, "Organized Labor in Business", 1930s (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group, correspondence, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Research Group files, stationery, 1930s (Box 3)
  - Felix S. Cohen, personal correspondence, 1935-1940 (Box 3)
  - Felix S. Cohen, personal correspondence, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Felix S. Cohen, personal correspondence, 1942; 2 (Box 3)
  - Felix S. Cohen, personal correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1939; 2 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, "non-Family interesting", 1933-1942 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, clippings, notes, circa 1934 (Box 4)
  - Invitations, Washington Committee for National Sharecroppers Tea, 1930 March 9; 2 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Notes and clippings (includes copy of Oklahoma Welfare Act with provisions of Indian Reorganization Act), 1936 June 26 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1930s, 1950s (Box 4)
  - Indians at Work, printed material, 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - Note cards, circa 1949; 2 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, notes and photographs related to appendectomy, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Kayser Silk hosiery box, 1930s (Box 4)
  - "Essentials of Rural Welfare", 1949 March (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Christmas cards, 1941; 2 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1938 (Box 5)
  - Erasmus High School report card, 1923 June (Box 5)
  - Helen Gahagan Douglas writings, 1948-1949 (Box 5)
  - Felix S. Cohen
    - Correspondence, legal writings and clippings related to Puerto Rican self-governance, 1943-1947 (Box 6)
    - "Congressional intent and attitude toward public law 600 and the constitution of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico", 1952 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and memoranda relating to Puerto Rico, 1940s (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and manuscript, "Reconstruction of hidden value judgments", 1942-1947 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and printed material related to Puerto Rico and the Puerto Rico Industrial Development Company, 1943-1948 (Box 6)
    - Legal papers and political reports on Puerto Rico Development plan, circa 1945; 2 (Box 6)
    - "The use and disposition of ships and shipyards at the end of World War II," printed material, 1945 June (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with Mr. Ironman, paper entitled "Law and Language", 1948-1953 (Box 6)
    - Typescripts and printed material related to an address entitled "Human and Natural Resources", 1945-1946 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and memoranda related to Puerto Rico tax exemption, 1948 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and printed material related to Puerto Rico, 1946-1950 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and clippings related to Puerto Rico, 1948 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence related to Puerto Rico, 1947-1950 (Box 6)
  - Clippings, theatrical programs and notes, circa 1980 (Box 6)
  - Photographs, personal and legal papers, pertaining to Lucy Kramer Cohen's fall and subsequent lawsuit against Western Hotels, Inc., 1957; 3 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, photograph and clipping from Harry Rosenfield, circa 1982 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, speech typescript, clippings and tax documents, 1968-1978 (Box 6)
  - Food and Drug Administration, publications and memoranda, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
  - Modern Maturity, 1963 April-May (Box 6)
  - Health Department documents, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Personal papers, clippings, publications by and about Lucy Kramer and Felix S. Cohen, 1933-1984 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, notes, clippings, 1985-1990; 2 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, clippings, notes, and speech typescripts related to bronze bust of Eleanor Roosevelt, 1963-1965 (Box 7)
  - Response to deposition of Margaret Herring, 1971 Dec 12 (Box 7)
  - Papers related to Cuban drug ransom, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Health care reports and notes, 1959-1962 (Box 7)
  - Clippings and printed material related to pharmaceutical industry, circa 1963 (Box 7)
  - "Hearings before the Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly", 1960 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1957; 2 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Misccellaneous correspondence, 1950s (Box 8)
  - Correspondence related to "Felix S. Cohen, Fighter for Justice", 1956 (Box 8)
  - Transcript of memorial service for Felix S. Cohen, 1953 Dec 4 (Box 8)
  - Notes, correspondence and clippings related to Felix S. Cohen's death and publications, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous personal and professional correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 8)
  - Answered mail and bills, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence regarding investments, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Felix Cohen's obitiuaries and memorial service preparations, circa 1953 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence regarding death of Felix Cohen, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence regarding job search and City College of New York booklet, circa 1955; 2 (Box 8)
  - Obituaries and memorial correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Felix S. Cohen obituaries, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Printed journals, 1920-1961; 3 (Box 8)
  - Letter regarding Nat Holman to The Campus, 1952 Nov 11 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 9)
  - Printed material, 1902-1960 (Box 9)
  - Sidney Kramer obituarities, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Anthropological journals, 1955-1961; 2 (Box 9)
  - Papers related to the American Anthropological Association meeting, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Reviews of The Legal Conscience, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Government career search info, circa 1956 (Box 9)
  - Address card organizers, undated; 3 (Box 10)
  - Personal correspondence, 1935 (Box 10)
  - Medical invoices, 1935-1936 (Box 10)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, printed material, 1931-1936 (Box 10)
  - Federal agricultural programs and union materials, printed, 1931-1935 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, clippings, and writings, 1938-1955 (Box 10)
  - Notes sent to [Arthur] E. Suffern of NYU School of Commerce, undated (Box 10)
  - Notes and correspondence related to the translation for the Encyclopedia of Social Services, 1933 (Box 10)
  - Mathematics teaching materials, circa 1933 (Box 10)
  - Kramer, Aaron; papers, legal records, correspondence, circa 1942; 3 (Box 10)
  - Capital City Forum, financial report, 1936-1937 (Box 10)
  - Lawyers' Committee on American Relations with Spain, circa 1938; 2 (Box 10)
  - Clippings about Spain, circa 1939; 2 (Box 10)
  - Clippings about Spain, circa 1939; 2 (Box 11)
  - Issues of Spain, 1937-1938 (Box 11)
  - Clippings related to the Spanish civil war and the Washington League of Women Shoppers, circa 1939 (Box 11)
  - Flyers and member literature for the Washington Consumers' Group and CO-OP, circa 1937 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, papers and correspondence, 1930-1938 (Box 11)
  - Manuscript of address, Radio Broadcast Institute of Living Law, undated (Box 11)
  - Consumers' Defender and Consumers' Research, 1934-1937 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence and Columbia University Bulletins, 1936-1938 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence and Bulletins related to the National Emergency Council, Consumers' Division, circa 1936 (Box 11)
  - Capital City Forum, correspondence and clippings, circa 1938; 2 (Box 11)
  - Jewish youth in New York City, printed material, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Papers from collaboration with Felix S. Cohen on Indian affairs, 1930s (Box 11)
  - Notes on immigration and refugees for Indian Department, 1939-1940 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence and writings related to Indian work, 1930s (Box 11)
  - "Red Man's Gifts," manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 11)
  - Notes and drafts of "Red Man's Gifts," chapters 1 and 2, circa 1936 (Box 11)
  - Course notes on Indian folklore, circa 1932 (Box 11)
  - Notes on Indian folklore, 1932 Oct (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, clippings and notes regarding North American Indians, circa 1935 (Box 11)
  - Topical Bibliography on Indians, 1930s (Box 11)
  - Timeline of early European exploration and discovery versus effect on Indians, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Civil service correspondence and employment application, circa 1956 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence related to federal employment loyalty investigation, 1952 Sep 3 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence regarding Lucy Kramer Cohen's employment qualifications, circa 1937 (Box 11)
  - Charts of egg and poulty statistics, 1930s-1940s (Box 11)
  - Correspondence regarding loyalty and security checks, 1952 Aug-Sep (Box 11)
  - Employment correspondence, circa 1952 (Box 11)
  - Employment notes (Box 11)
  - Federal employment legislation, notes and printed material, circa 1951 (Box 12)
  - Department of Indian Affairs and history thereof, correspondence and notes, circa 1938 (Box 12)
  - "Red Man's Gifts to America", manuscript and notes, 1936 (Box 12)
  - "450 years of White-Indian relations", radio program transcript by Indian Bureau, 1937 Mar (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous employment documents and correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 12)
  - Job search, circa 1947 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence related to job search, 1947-1949 (Box 12)
  - Notes and printed material related to history of Indian law, 1927-1937 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence and research notes on Indian culture, history and language, circa 1935 (Box 12)
  - Printed material and research notes on Indians, 1935-1938 (Box 12)
  - Printed materials and speech draft related to the Department of Labor, 1944-1951; 2 (Box 12)
  - Printed material related to Public Health, 1960s; 4 (Box 12)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization, printed material, 1948-1949 (Box 12)
  - Statistical tables related to CO-Op drug benefits, circa 1962 (Box 12)
  - Women's Bureau report, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - "Coverage of Domestic Servants in Foreign Insurance Plans", 1939 (Box 12)
  - The President's Committee on Scientists and Engineers, printed material, 1958 (Box 13)
  - "Indians: Yesterday and Today", includes two chapters by Lucy M. Kramer, 1941 Jul (Box 13)
  - Issues of "Indians at Work" which contain articles by Lucy M. Kramer, 1936-1942 (Box 13)
  - "Indians at Work," 10 issues containing articles by Lucy Kramer Cohen, 1939 Feb; 2 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous government documents, 1957-1962 (Box 13)
  - "Education and training for the changing role of public health in society", 1963 Aug (Box 13)
  - Research materials and scientific and technical labor force, 1956-1957 (Box 13)
  - Scholarship and employment clearance, 1956 (Box 13)
  - Calendar pad, 1956 (Box 13)
  - Desk calendar, "The Ever Ready Calendar", 1951 Jan-Jun (Box 13)
  - Curriculum vitae drafts and personnel material, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - Helen Gahagan Douglas voting record, circa 1950 (Box 13)
  - Forms and correspondence related to loyalty investigation, crica 1952 (Box 13)
  - Job application materials and publications, 1944-1948 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous public health documents and publications, 1960-1968 (Box 13)
  - National War Labor Board documents, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
  - Steel Commission report to the National War Labor Board, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
  - Guaranteed annual wage report to the National War Labor Board, 1944-1945 (Box 14)
  - Labor Board reports, documents and publications, 1942-1951 (Box 14)
  - "Wages in the basic lumber industry in the far west, 1944" preliminary draft, 1945 May 21 (Box 14)
  - West Coast Lumber Commission documents, 1944-1946 (Box 14)
  - "Job Description for Wage Studies: Metalworking", 1945 Nov 1 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
  - Reports, memoranda and printed material related to the West Coast Labor Commission, veteran's rights and the National Conciliation Service, 1942-1946 (Box 14)
  - Health Benefit plan research materials, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
  - Report on labor associations, 1946 Oct 4 (Box 14)
  - "Union Rights and Responsibilities", 1946 Aug 1 (Box 14)
  - "Grievance Procedure under Collective Bargaining", 1946 Oct 9 (Box 14)
  - Production reports, 1946-1947 (Box 14)
  - Union Reports, 1946 June (Box 14)
  - Uniform Termination Dates research, 1946 Jun 7 (Box 14)
  - Wage reopening research, 1946 Jun 8 (Box 14)
  - Textile Workers' Union, correspondence and notes, 1946-1947 (Box 14)
  - National War Labor Board, miscellaneous documents, circa 1946; 2 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department Personnel documents, 1946-1947 (Box 14)
  - "Efficiency Rating Instructions", 1947 Mar 19-21 (Box 14)
  - "Extent of Collective Bargaining and Union Recognition, 1946", 1947 Apr 21 (Box 14)
  - Subject File Index Labor Department, 1946 Nov 1 (Box 14)
  - Marquart Memos, 1946-1947 (Box 14)
  - "Filing System for Clippings", 1946 Oct 15 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department, miscellaneous documents, circa 1946 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department, miscellaneous notes, 1946-1947 (Box 14)
  - "Wage Stabilization Manual", 1944-1946 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department, miscellaneous notes, 1946-1947 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department Publications, 1946 (Box 14)
  - Textile Commission Publications, 1945 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department union pamphlets, 1941-1946 (Box 14)
  - Labor Department miscellaneous publications, 1945-1946 (Box 15)
  - Bulletin 686 outlines, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Bulletin 686 preliminary drafts of chapters, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Union Agreement Expiration list, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Wage agreement correspondence and reports, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous copying projects, circa 1947 (Box 15)
  - Memo, "extent of collective bargaining study", 1947 Feb 1 (Box 15)
  - Industry-wide bargaining, History of Pottery, Women's clothing industry, 1947 Feb (Box 15)
  - Personnel memoranda regarding promotions and pay increase, 1942-1946 (Box 15)
  - "Union Security" (Preliminary Draft), 1946 Oct 15 (Box 15)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act Interpretive Bulletins, circa 1939 (Box 15)
  - National Wage Stabilization Board, releases and clippings, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Public Health Services commissioned corps pay scale, 1973 Jan 1 (Box 15)
  - Employment documents and "Scientific and Technological Manpower News Round-up", 1957 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Labor Department and Food and Agriculture Organization, 1947-1952 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Labor Department documents, 1951-1952; 2 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Civil Service notice of rating, 1951 (Box 15)
  - Research materials and employment documents, 1970s (Box 15)
  - Personnel correspondence (labeled "Private"), 1976 (Box 15)
  - Retirement material, 1969-1973 (Box 15)
  - "Health Manpower Issues", 1975 Nov 13 (Box 15)
  - Reference correspondence and employment applications, 1938-1951 (Box 15)
  - Employment correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 15)
  - Employment correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box 15)
  - Employment correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 15)
  - "Survey of Current Business", profiles of the incomes of physicians, dentists, and lawyers, circa 1949 (Box 15)
  - Employment and reference correspondence, circa 1950 (Box 15)
  - Speech of Helen Gahagan Douglas entitled "Cost of Living", 1948 (Box 15)
  - Research notes for Helen Gahagan Douglas, 1949-1950 (Box 15)